# JeffRowe



Contact Camarillo, CA 93012 USA

+1 (805) 300 9067

# **Languages**English native Russian experienced

# Programming Languages

♥ Python SQL, Spark, Scala, धर्FX

#### **Frameworks**

Tensorflow, Flask, Plotly Dash, Scikit-learn, Beautiful Soup, AWS Sagemaker

## **Skills**

Descriptive Data
Analysis, Linear and
Logistic Regression,
SVD and K-clustering,
Natural Language
Processing, Web
Scraping, SHAP Values
and Partial
Dependence Plots,
Dashboards and Data
Visualization,
Hyperparameterization

### Technology Platforms

AWS: EC2, S3, RDS, Sagemaker, Elastic Beanstalk, Lambda Email: jeffrowe822@gmail.com

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/rowebyrowe/

Github: https://github.com/rowebyrowe Portfolio:http://rowebyrowe.com/

# **Summary**

Data Scientist with a year's worth of experience in coding, modeling, and pipelining. Equally at home with data munging, modeling, and creating visualizations. Great at interpreting needs and implementing those into usable code. Strong written and verbal communications.

# **Projects**

2019 Groa Movie Recommender

Eight week project

Word2vec|Beautiful Soup|NLP|AWS Lambda|AWS Elastic Beanstalk|PostgreSQL|Flask

- Collaborated with a team of four other data scientists across three time-zones
- Scraped millions of movie reviews to be used by the recommender model
- Solely responsible for developing the front end and the back end of the user facing site
- Designed a Flask front end API for fast inferencing with standardized data
- · Assisted with making the model more specialized to the users

# **Experience**

2019 **Lambda School** 

Remote

Team Lead

- Mentored 8 students on how to learn effectively and solve programming problems
- Track student attendance, grade evaluation projects, and complete student progress reports
- Led daily stand-up meetings to build camaraderie, facilitate the sharing of ideas and work progress, and provide guidance for that week's study material

#### 2016-2017 Manhattan Gulch LLC

Round Mountain, Nevada

Lead Tester

- Visited dig sites to test gold concentration
- Based on said concentration, instructed digging team whether to mine or move to a new area

#### 2016 Manhattan Gulch LLC

Round Mountain, Nevada

Gold Purifier

- · Worked with a team of three
- Trusted with mechanically separating ounces of gold from 40 liters of material daily
- Handled opening and closing of facilities

### 2016-2020 **Freelance**

Remote

English Teacher

- Taught classes in groups sizes of up to 30 students
- Used total physical response to keep the students engaged and provide deeper connection to the material
- Tutored special classes in Mathematics and Physics

## **Education**

2019–2020 Data Science Fellowship Coursework:
 Computer Science, Predictive and Descriptive Statistics, Data Engineering, Relational and Non-Relational Databases, Natural Language Processing, Neural Networks, Machine Learning

 2011–2016 Ba. Science in Biochemistry Brigham Young University

(Emphasis in Statistical Ánalysis) GPA:3.18